[{"question": "Three abstract layers in UNIX OS are:", "answer": "user processes, kernel, hardware", "answers": ["user processes, kernel, hardware", "kernel, debian, ubuntu", "etc, home, documents", "none of the above"]}, {"question": "For operating system RAM is a...", "answer": "all of the above", "answers": ["set of 0 and 1", "space to store user processes and kernel", "direct read/write space for CPU", "all of the above"]}, {"question": "What is NOT true about processes?", "answer": "Only one process of same program can be run at once.", "answers": ["Process is something currently under execution.", "Can be executed by multiple threads.", "Only one process of same program can be run at once.", "Process is an instance of a program."]}, {"question": "Kernel is responsible for...", "answer": "Only one process of same program can be run at once.", "answers": ["all of the below.", "managing access of processes to CPU.", "managing memory and assigning it to preccess.", "establishing interface between user processes and hardware."]}, {"question": "'Time slice' is...", "answer": "an amount of time assign to a process by a kernel.", "answers": ["a timestamp object.", "an amount of time assign to a process by a kernel.", "a slice of string type date.", "a value set as a time of execution for a process."]}, {"question": "In UNIX systems, kernel ___ assign private slice of memory for itself.", "answer": "must", "answers": ["must", "can", "can't", "musn't"]}, {"question": "What is a 'swap partition' used for?", "answer": "For allowing kernel to use more RAM than it is physically possible.", "answers": ["To keep sleeping processes.", "For storing kernel.", "Doesn't exist in UNIX OS.", "For allowing kernel to use more RAM than it is physically possible."]}, {"question": "What is a 'swap partition' used for?", "answer": "For allowing kernel to use more RAM than it is physically possible.", "answers": ["To keep sleeping processes.", "For storing kernel.", "Doesn't exist in UNIX OS.", "For allowing kernel to use more RAM than it is physically possible."]}, {"question": "Kernel identifies users by ...", "answer": "userid", "answers": ["username", "userid", "timestamp", "hashed passwd"]}, {"question": "Bash is ...", "answer": "a program executing commands.", "answers": ["a program executing commands.", "not accessible with GUI.", "object-oriented programming language", "stored is /etc"]}, {"question": "Bash is ...", "answer": "a scripting programming language.", "answers": ["not a part of UNIX OS.", "can only be executed directly in Terminal.", "not accessible with GUI.", "a scripting programming language."]}, {"question": "Which bash command will move pwd to /home?", "answer": "cd /~", "answers": ["cd /~", "HOME$", "mk /~", "cd /"]}, {"question": "Which bash command will allow to delete directory 'my_dir' with files in it?", "answer": "rm -rf my_dir", "answers": ["rmdir my_dir", "rm -rf my_dir", "rmdir my_dir -rf", "rmdir -rf my_dir"]}, {"question": "Which bash command will list out all files with .csv extnesion?", "answer": "ls -a *.csv", "answers": ["ls ?.csv", "ls .csv", "ls -a *.csv", "ls | echo *.csv"]}, {"question": "Which bash command will print all lines containing 'root' from /etc/passwd", "answer": "grep root /etc/passwd", "answers": ["more root /etc/passwd", "find root", "grep root /etc/passwd", "grep root /etc/passwd"]}, {"question": "'$head 5 my_file.csv > report.txt' will ... ", "answer": "redirect stdout to overwrite report.txt", "answers": ["will append report.txt with first 5 lines of my_file.csv", "return error", "print first 5 lines in terminal and save it in result.txt", "redirect stdout to overwrite report.txt"]}, {"question": "asd", "answer": "asd", "answers": ["asd", []]}, {"question": "dsadsa", "answer": "dsadasd", "answers": ["asdasdad", "dsadasd", "asdasd", "asdasd"]}, {"question": "asd", "answer": "asd", "answers": ["asd", "asd", ""]}]